Register of the Portuguese Subject Collection, 1970-1991
Hoover Institution Archives
Portuguese Subject Collection,
1970-1991
75048
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Pamphlets, leaflets, and serial issues, relating to the Portuguese revolution of 1974, and to Portuguese foreign relations, trade unions, and armed forces.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1975.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Portugal.; Portugal--History--Revolution, 1974.; Portugal--Foreign relations.; Trade-unions--Portugal.; Portugal--Armed Forces.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1970-1991. (Box 1)
  Brochures, flyers, leaflets, newspaper issues, poem, and speeches relating to the political and social history of Portugal, arranged chronologically and then alphabetically by subject.
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been received after Dec. 1994.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1970-1991.
  - 1933-1974
    - Economy. Speeches by Minister of Agriculture Vasco Lesnidas, 1970, relating to Portuguese labor. In Portuguese (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Foreign policy. Speech by Ambassador to Brazil Josi Manuel Fragoso, 1970, relating to Portuguese foreign policy. In Portuguese (Folder 2)
    - Miscellany. Poem by Jaime Cortesco, n.d. (in Portuguese), and pamphlet issued by Radio Portugal-Lisbon, n.d. (in English) (Folder 3)
  - 1974. Newspaper issues and flyers relating to the Revolution of April 1974. In Portuguese (Folder 4)
  - 1974-
    - Communist Party. Flyers and leaflets, 1974-1975. Includes flyers by splinter-groups. In Portuguese (Folder 5)
    - Eanes, Ramalho. Speech by President Eanes, 1976. In Portuguese (Folder 6)
    - Elections- 1991. Newspaper issues and brochures, 1990-1991, issued by the Socialist Party of President Mario Soares for the presidential election of January 13, 1991. In Portuguese (Folder 7)